orbitzforbusiness.net 2016-10-28

# Orbitz for Business: Privacy Policy

Effective July 01, 2015

## Orbitz for Business® Privacy Policy

Your privacy is very important to Orbitz for Business, Inc. This Privacy Policy describes the principles and practices that apply to Personal Information (defined below) collected from users of our services ("you") on our Site (defined below) and from third party accounts to which you permit us access.

Your organization has elected to have us offer our corporate travel services to you pursuant to a corporate agreement and subject to this Privacy Policy. Our Site is not intended for, nor is it accessible to, the general public. Your organization's policies may differ from those set forth in this Privacy Policy, and we are not responsible for any use or disclosure of your Personal Information by anyone at your organization.

The remainder of this policy describes our Personal Information handling practices in detail.

1\. Definitions  
2\. Consent  
3\. What Personal Information we collect  
4\. How we use the information we collect  
5\. To whom we disclose Personal Information  
6\. How we retain and store Personal Information  
7\. How we protect Personal Information  
8\. How to access, modify or close your account  
9\. Privacy  
10.Changes to the Privacy Policy  
11.Disputes  
12.U.S.-EU and U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor Frameworks  
13.Your California Rights  
14.Contact Information  

> In this Privacy Policy, terms that commence with a capital letter are defined in this Section.
> 
> **"Book"** means to reserve.
> 
> **"Guest Member"** means an individual who has been invited to register on the Site by an organization with a relationship with Orbitz for Business, Inc. A Guest Member may be given limited rights to access and use the Site, including but not limited to restrictions based on term of membership and access to individual Products or Services.
> 
> **"Member"** means an individual who has registered on the www.orbitzforbusiness.net site.
> 
> **"Member ID"** means the e-mail address Members use (with their password) to log into our Site.
> 
> **"Orbitz for Business," "us," "our"** or **"we"** means Orbitz for Business, Inc.
> 
> **"Personal Information"** means any information, recorded in any form, about an identified individual, or an individual whose identity may be inferred from the information. This includes, for example, name, e-mail and mailing address, telephone number, billing and account information, passport and visa information and other information incidental to providing Products or Services (including information about individuals traveling with an individual who Books on our Site).
> 
> **"Products or Services"** means the airline travel, hotel accommodation, car rental, ground transportation, rail transportation, alerts, and other items available from our Site.
> 
> **"Session Data"** means usage information, such as the type of Internet browser and operating system an individual uses, the domain name of the site from which the individual came, the date, time and duration of the individual's visit, the number of visits to our Site, the pages viewed and the number of cookies accumulated, and, in the case of the Orbitz for Business mobile site, also means the unique identifier of an individual's mobile device, the type of mobile device the individual uses and the application version.
> 
> **"Site"** means the [www.orbitzforbusiness.net](https://orbitzforbusiness.net/) site, the m.orbitzforbusiness.net mobile site or the [www.orbitzforbusiness.com](http://orbitzforbusiness.com/) site and their respective sub sites together with the respective content, Products and Services available from these sites or sub sites.

> BY SUBMITTING PERSONAL INFORMATION TO US, AND/OR BY USING OUR SITE, AND/OR BY PERMITTING US ACCESS TO YOUR THIRD PARTY ACCOUNTS, YOU AGREE THAT WE MAY COLLECT, USE AND DISCLOSE SUCH PERSONAL INFORMATION IN ACCORDANCE WITH THIS PRIVACY POLICY AND AS PERMITTED OR REQUIRED BY LAW.
> 
> If you do not agree with the terms set forth below, do not provide any Personal Information to us. If you choose not to provide us with any required Personal Information, or if you withdraw your consent, we may not be able to provide you Products or Services.
> 
> **Minors**
> 
> Minors (as defined under the laws of their jurisdiction or residence) are not eligible to register for, use or Book the Products or Services. Since our Site is only accessible to corporate organizations, we do not believe we are collecting information from Minors, nor do we do knowingly collect Personal Information from any Minor, and will not use this information if we discover that it has been provided by a Minor.
> 
> **Other Travelers or Contacts**
> 
> If you Book Products or Services for other travelers, or if you provide us with contact information of a third party for Orbitz Care Alerts, you must make sure that you have the right to do so. By providing the Personal Information of another traveler or third party, you represent that you have all necessary authority and/or have obtained all necessary consents from such person to enable us to collect, use and disclose his or her Personal Information as set forth in this Privacy Policy. This includes corporate travel administers or arrangers who Book Products or Services for other travelers - corporate travel administers and arrangers must ensure that the traveler receives and agrees to the terms set forth in this Privacy Policy.

3\. 

_What Personal Information we collect_   

> **When you register as a Member or a Guest Member**
> 
> When you register with us as a Member or a Guest Member, you must provide your name, e-mail address and organization's name. If you consented to have your organization share your personal travel information with us, we will match the limited information you provide with the travel profile you may have provided your organization. If you did not consent to your organization sharing your personal travel information with us, we may ask for your consent to obtain your travel profile from your organization. The travel profile will include Personal Information that you provided your organization, such as your mailing address, travel loyalty numbers and credit card numbers for travel bookings. Your consent for your organization to share your personal travel information with us may be necessary for you to become a Member. You also must choose a password, which will be required to gain access to our Site. We might also request your home zip code passport number, and visa number(s).
> 
> You may elect to provide other information. Such information may include, for example, gender, travel loyalty numbers, travel special requests, Personal Information of your administrative assistant (if applicable) and emergency contacts.
> 
> **When you Book Products or Services as a Member**
> 
> When you Book Products or Services as a Member, you must provide payment and billing information and other information required by the travel service provider(s). Such information may include, for example, date of birth, gender, driver information or similar information.
> 
> **When you Book Products or Services for a third party**
> 
> When you Book Products or Services for a third party, you must provide that third party's name and contact information, payment and billing information and other information required by the travel service provider(s).
> 
> **When you participate in a survey or a focus group**
> 
> From time to time, we may invite you to participate in a survey or a focus group. You are free to participate or not.
> 
> **When you permit us access to your third party accounts**
> 
> We may offer you the option of permitting us access to your third party accounts, such as your TripIt account. We may view and use any information stored in such third party accounts in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

4.

 _How we use the information we collect_   

> **Personal Information**
> 
> We use Personal Information in order to provide and enhance the Products or Services offered:
> 
>   * To record your travel preferences, make reservations or acquire travel insurance on your behalf or communicate with you about your travel plans;
>   * To issue invoices, administer accounts, collect and process payments;
>   * To provide tips or guidance on how to use our Site, inform you of new features on our Site or provide other information that may be of interest to users;
>   * To personalize the service we provide to you, tailor your experience at our Site to your interests and make more appropriate travel recommendations;
>   * To send you e-mails, e-newsletters, personalized offers via direct messaging or other communications about our services, if you have subscribed to receive this information or you have not advised us that you do not wish to receive such communications;
>   * To manage our Site, diagnose technical problems, improve content and allocate the resources of our systems so that your experience with our Site is as efficient as possible;
>   * To process and track your transactions and to send you information about our and our affiliates' and business partners' products and services and other information and materials that may be of interest to you;
>   * To develop, enhance, market, sell or provide Orbitz for Business' Products or Services, or those of companies with which we have a commercial relationship, but only if you have granted us permission to do so or we are otherwise able to do so under applicable law;
>   * To send your organization information about your use or non-use of our Site, which we may obtain from your third party accounts to which you permit us access;
>   * To evaluate credit standing and to match credit bureau or credit reporting agency information;
>   * To investigate, detect and protect Orbitz for Business, Members and other third parties against error, negligence, breach of contract, fraud, theft and other illegal activities;
>   * To effect a corporate transaction in connection with the sale, merger, spin-off or other corporate reorganization of our corporation, where the information is provided to the new controlling entity in regular course of business;
>   * To audit compliance with our policies and contractual obligations;
>   * As permitted by, and to comply with, any legal or regulatory requirements or provisions; or
>   * For any other purpose to which you consent.
> 

> 
> **Session Data**
> 
> We use Session Data, collected through network monitoring tools,cookies and pixel tags, to better understand how our Site is navigated, how many visitors arrive at specific pages, the length and frequency of stays at our Site, the variety of searches of our Site's database, the types of browsers and computer operating systems used by our visitors and the Internet Protocol addresses from which visitors connect to our Site.
> 
> We also use this information to improve our Site's content and ease of use, to personalize and improve your individual viewing experiences on our Site and provide information that may be of interest to you.
> 
> **Aggregated Information**
> 
> Aggregated information is information recorded in any form about more than one individual, where the identity of the individual is not known and cannot be inferred from the information. We may use aggregated information to describe our user base to current or potential partners, investors and advertisers; after a survey, to understand and respond to market needs and preferences; or to make recommendations to other users of our Site. For example, if users of our Site who have traveled to a particular destination told us that they had positive experiences at a hotel in that destination, we might recommend that hotel.
> 
> **What we do NOT do**
> 
> We do not and will not, at any time, request your credit card information, Member ID, password or national identification numbers in a non-secure or unsolicited e-mail or telephone communication.
> 
> Identity theft and the practice currently known as "phishing" are of great concern to us. Safeguarding information to help protect you from identity theft is our priority. For more information about phishing, you may want to visit the Federal Trade Commission at <http://www.ftc.gov/bcp/edu/pubs/consumer/alerts/alt127.shtm>

5.

 _To whom we disclose Personal Information_   

> From time to time, we may disclose your Personal Information as follows:
> 
>   * To those travel service providers with which you make arrangements through our Site, for example airlines, car rental, hotel, ground transportation, or rail transportation. We provide them with the Personal Information needed to make and complete the booking or reservation;
>   * To organizations that perform services for or on behalf of Orbitz for Business, for example to provide customer service, deliver tickets, ship items, process credit cards, for research, data processing, to measure the use of our Site, to facilitate usage by a visitor or to offer credit card services or evaluate your creditworthiness. We will share with these companies only that Personal Information which they need to work on our behalf. Some of these service providers may be located in countries outside the US and outside the European Economic Area ("EEA").Your Personal Information will be provided to these organizations only if they agree to use such information solely for the purpose of providing services to Orbitz for Business, and under the instructions of Orbitz for Business, and with respect to that information, to act in a manner consistent with the relevant principles articulated in this Policy. By submitting your personal data, you agree to the transfer, storing and processing of your data outside the US and outside the EEA;
>   * To your organization about your use or non-use of the Site;
>   * To protect our Site and our rights under our [Terms and Conditions](https://www.orbitzforbusiness.net/pagedef/content/legal/terms05_.jsp?popupsDisabled=false); to protect ourselves against liability or prevent fraudulent activity; or where it is necessary to permit us to pursue available remedies or limit any damages that we may sustain;
>   * To effect a corporate transaction, in connection with the sale, merger, spin-off or other corporate reorganization of our corporation, where the information is provided to the new controlling entity in connection with that business transaction;
>   * Where the information is public; or
>   * To our insurers and to regulatory agencies to the extent required by law.
> 

> 
> **Disclosure without Consent**
> 
> **_Please note that there are circumstances where the use or disclosure of Personal Information may be justified or permitted, or where Orbitz for Business may be obligated to disclose information without consent._**
> 
> Such circumstances may include: 
> 
>   * If required to comply with a subpoena or warrant issued or an order made by a court, person or body with jurisdiction to compel the production of information or to comply with the rules of a court relating to the production of records;
> 
> If we receive a formal request to disclose your Personal Information in connection with a legal action, we will attempt to contact you about it, if permitted by law, via the e-mail address you provided during registration, before we respond to that request.
> 
>   * If we believe in good faith that a law, regulation, rule or guideline requires it; 
>   * To a person who needs the information because of an emergency that threatens the life, health or security of an identifiable person or group; or 
>   * Where it is necessary to collect monies owing to us.
> 

> 
> **National Security**
> 
> In order to protect national security and to ensure travel security, the United States government and other governments may lawfully compel us to provide passenger name records, which typically includes name, flight origin, flight destination, flight time, duration of flight, seat location, travel agent, form of payment, credit card numbers, travel itinerary, address, telephone number and meal requests. In response to such government requests, Orbitz for Business and/or its providers will provide access to the information you provide at the time of making the booking to the applicable government agencies of the countries to or from which you are traveling.

6.

 _How we retain and store Personal information_   

> **My Trips and My Account**
> 
> We store your Personal Information in My Trips, My Account and My Travel Arrangers. You can access My Trips and My Account from the [home page](https://www.orbitzforbusiness.net/Secure/OFBSignIn) of our Site, after logging onto our Site. My Trips contains information about your current, canceled or past trips. My Account contains your name, e-mail address, e-mail and password settings, and departure city from which you usually travel. It may also contain other information so that you do not need to re-enter it each time you Book a Product or Service. For example, My Account may contain your billing information unless you tell us not to store it. It may also contain your preferences for seat selection or special meals, details about your participation in loyalty or awards programs and applicable membership numbers, passport number, visa number(s) and other travel preferences. We also keep in My Account all other information that your organization has provided or that you have elected to provide us, such as gender, travel loyalty numbers, travel special requests, Personal Information of your administrative assistant (if applicable) and emergency contacts. My Travel Arrangers contains a list of individuals within your organization who have the ability to Book Products and Services on your behalf. 
> 
> You can access, modify or close your account as described in How to access, modify, or close your account.
> 
> **Third Parties' Personal Information**
> 
> We will retain in your My Account, the Personal Information of individuals for whom you have made reservations or to whom we have sent Orbitz Care Alerts on your behalf.
> 
> You can access or modify these third parties' Personal Information at any time, as described in How to access, modify, or close your account.
> 
> **Retention and Storage**
> 
> We will retain your Personal Information in our databases in accordance with our Records Management Policy and applicable laws. This period may extend beyond the end of your relationship with us, but it will be only as long as it is necessary for us to have sufficient information to respond to any issues that may arise later. For example, we may need or be required to retain information to allow you to obtain credit for a trip you Booked but had to cancel. We may also need to retain certain information to prevent fraudulent activity; protect ourselves against liability, permit us to pursue available remedies or limit any damages that we may sustain; or if we believe in good faith that a law, regulation, rule or guideline requires it.
> 
> Your Personal Information will be stored in secured locations and on servers controlled by Orbitz for Business, located either at our offices or at the offices of our service providers as described in How we protect Personal Information.

7.

 _How we protect Personal Information_   

> Orbitz for Business employs physical, administrative and technical safeguards designed to help protect the confidentiality and integrity of Personal Information and to reduce the risk of loss, misuse, unauthorized access, disclosure or modification of Personal Information. When Personal Information is sent to our service providers, we require them by contract to protect all Personal Information in a manner consistent with the principles articulated in this Privacy Policy.
> 
> If you choose to contact Orbitz for Business through our Site, you should be aware that any information transmitted electronically via the World Wide Web might not be secure. Orbitz for Business assumes no liability for the loss of any information that you transmit to us via the World Wide Web. However, if you provide your credit card information on our Site's credit card forms or if you choose to search for Products and Services, through the Orbitz for Business mobile applications, that are located near you and we collect your geo-location, we encrypt the transmission of that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL).
> 
> In communicating with you, we may send e-mail as unencrypted plain text because we are aware that most Members and Guests cannot readily process encrypted e-mail. This is done for your convenience, but with the security concern that, if misrouted or intercepted, it could be read more easily than encrypted e-mail.

8.

 _How to access, modify or close your Account_   

> We endeavor to ensure that Personal Information is as accurate, complete and current as necessary for the purposes for which we use that information. We encourage you to visit [My Account](https://www.orbitzforbusiness.net/Secure/OFBSignIn) to review your Personal Information.
> 
> You can access your Personal Information in My Account and update it or delete inaccuracies, as necessary. For example, you can change at any time, except as limited by your organization, your e-mail address, travel loyalty numbers, travel special requests, Personal Information of your administrative assistant (if applicable) and emergency contacts or your preferences for receiving or not receiving our e-mails.
> 
> If you contact us, as indicated in Contact Information, to request a modification to your Personal Information, we will respond within 30 days. For some changes, you may need to contact your organization's travel administrator.
> 
> If you wish that we close your account, you must contact your organization's travel administrator. The ability to close your account may be limited by your organization. Once your account is closed, you will not be able to use many of the services available on our Site to Members, unless you re-register.
> 
> Please remember that we may not be able to honor your request if we are legally obligated to retain information, or for other reasons described in Retention and Storage.

> **Cookies**
> 
> We use cookies to understand how you use our Site, tailor our Site for you and to manage and improve our Site. A cookie is a small data file that is transferred to your computer, stored in user's web browser and contains data used when the user is browsing on the website. Most Internet browsers automatically accept cookies. You can instruct your browser, by changing its settings, to stop accepting cookies or to prompt you before accepting a cookie from the websites you visit. Please be aware that you will not be able to make a travel booking and some of our Services may not function properly if you disable cookies.
> 
> We use several types of cookies. 
> 
>   * Session cookies are used to make our Site function correctly and to ensure your experience on our Site is seamlessly executed by our infrastructure. These cookies typically expire after you leave our Site.
>   * Persistent cookies are used to remember your preferences and information about your previous interactions on our Site and to enhance your experience on our Site. For example, these cookies remember a user's preference to store their email address and auto-populate the email field on the log-in page.
>   * Analytics cookies are used to understand how you interact with our Site over time and across devices. For example, we collect information about which pages you view, your interaction with these pages and how you navigated to these pages. 
> 

> 
> We work with companies who may need to use cookies to provide their services to us (known as third party cookies). For example, these companies may track how you navigated to our Site. Some of these companies may combine anonymous information obtained in connection with your interaction with our Site with information obtained from other sources and/or your behavior on other websites. 
> 
> We may use pixel tags and web beacons to understand how you interact with our Site and communications, to improve our Services. For example, this allows us to determine whether you have interacted with an email from us. 
> 
> Some browsers have a "Do Not Track" feature that allows you to tell websites that you do not want to have your activities tracked. Our Site does not have the functionality supporting a 'Do Not Track' browser setting.
> 
> **Opting-Out**
> 
> At any time you may change which of the e-mail communications you wish to receive or not, by changing your preferences as described in How to access, modify or close your account.
> 
> **Monitoring**
> 
> Orbitz for Business may from time to time monitor and review any information transmitted or received through our Site, or through telephone or e-mail communications, for quality assurance and other purposes. We reserve the right to censor, edit, remove or prohibit the transmission or receipt of any information that Orbitz for Business deems inappropriate or in violation of our [Terms and Conditions](https://www.orbitzforbusiness.net/pagedef/content/legal/terms05_.jsp?popupsDisabled=false). During monitoring the information may be examined, recorded or copied.
> 
> **Links**
> 
> When you click on a third party's link from our Site, you will entering that third party's site, over which we have no control. We are not responsible for third party sites. You should carefully review the privacy statements of any other sites you visit, because those privacy statements will apply to your visit to such other sites and may be very different from this Privacy Policy.

10.

 _Changes to the Privacy Policy_   

> **Changes to the Privacy Policy and Changes in Ownership**
> 
> We may change or supplement this Privacy Policy from time to time. We may also undergo a change of ownership. Privacy Policy changes will apply to the information collected from the date we post the revised Privacy Policy to our Site, as well as to existing information held by us.
> 
> If we decide to change this policy in a material way, we will obtain the necessary consents required under applicable privacy laws if we seek to collect, use or disclose Personal Information for purposes other than those to which consent has been obtained, unless otherwise required or permitted by law. If we make any material changes we will notify your organization's travel administrator, notify you by e-mail (at the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on our Site prior to the change becoming effective. If you have questions or concerns about any proposed change, please contact your organization's travel administrator.

> Orbitz for Business has been awarded TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this Privacy Policy and Orbitz for Business' practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with [TRUSTe's program requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy_seals_and_services/consumer_privacy/privacy-programs-requirements.html) including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal information. TRUSTe's mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy trustmark and innovative trust solutions. The TRUSTe program only covers information collected through our Site.
> 
> If you have questions or concerns regarding Orbitz for Business privacy practices, you should first contact us as indicated in Contact Information. If you feel your inquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, you should then contact [TRUSTe here](http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint). TRUSTe will serve as a liaison with Orbitz for Business to resolve your concerns.

12.

 _U.S.-EU and U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor Frameworks_   

> Orbitz for Business is headquartered in the United States. If you are using our Services from outside the United States, you agree that Personal Information may be transferred to and processed in the United States and other locations.
> 
> Orbitz for Business complies with the U.S. - E.U. & U.S. - Swiss Safe Harbor Frameworks as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use and retention of personal data from the European Union and Switzerland. Orbitz for Business adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access and enforcement. Information regarding the U.S. - E.U. & U.S. - Swiss Safe Harbor Frameworks can be found at: <http://export.gov/safeharbor>. As part of our participation in the Safe Harbor Frameworks, we have agreed to TRUSTe dispute resolution for disputes relating to our compliance with the Safe Harbor Privacy Framework. If you have any complaints regarding our compliance with the Safe Harbor Frameworks you should first contact us. If contacting us does not resolve your complaint, you may raise your complaint with TRUSTe [here](http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint&url=).The TRUSTe dispute resolution process will be conducted in English.

13.

 _Your California Rights_   

> California residents have the right to request in writing from businesses with whom they have an established business relationship, (a) a list of the categories of personal information, such as name, e-mail and mailing address and the type of services provided to the customer, that a business has disclosed to third parties (including affiliates that are separate legal entities) during the immediately preceding calendar year for the third parties' direct marketing purposes and (b) the names and addresses of all such third parties. If you are a resident of California and have an established business relationship with us, you may request the above information by e-mailing us at:customerservice@orbitzforbusiness.net or write to us at: Orbitz for Business, Inc., Attn: Customer Service - Privacy, 500 West Madison Street, Suite 1000, Chicago, IL 60661 with a reference to California Disclosure Information.
> 
> We will respond to such requests to information access within 30 days following receipt at the e-mail or mailing address stated above. If we receive your request at a different e-mail or mailing address, we will respond within a reasonable period of time, but not to exceed 150 days from the date received. Please note that we are only required to respond to each customer once per calendar year.

> If you have any questions or concerns about (a) this Privacy Policy, (b) the collection, use, management or disclosure of your Personal Information or (c) accessing, modifying or closing your account, you may contact us as indicated below. We will attempt to respond to your questions or concerns promptly after we receive them.
> 
> E-mail:| [customerservice@orbitzforbusiness.net](mailto:customerservice@orbitzforbusiness.net)  
> ---|---  
> Mail:| Orbitz for Business, Inc., Attn: Customer Service - Privacy,   
>  500 West Madison Street, Suite 1000  
>  Chicago, IL 60661  
> Telephone:|  (within the United States)  
>  (Outside the United States).
